

# Sergiy Ponomarenko

### Python Developer

- Kyiv, Ukraine
- **J** +380 93 563 29 53
- g sergiy.ponomarenko@gmail.com
- https://sergiokapone.github.io

### Social Network ——

- in LinkedIn
- Github

### Languages

- Ukrainian (Native)

### Tech Skills

- Python
- Django
- Flask
- Jinja2
- FastAPI
- SQL
- SQLAlchemy
- Alembic
- Redis
- RabbitMQ
- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL
- JavaScript
- Bootstrap
- HTML / CSS
- Git
- Linux
- Docker
- ETFX

#### **About Me**

I am a physicist with a doctoral degree in physics of polymers. I have teaching experience and a passion for programming.

My research and teaching background has allowed me to utilize programming, especially Python, for automating routine tasks, analyzing and processing complex data, visualizing physical phenomena, and modeling physical processes.

I always strive to improve my skills and explore new technologies. I enjoy working in the areas of data analysis, modeling of physical systems and processes, and software development for scientific and engineering tasks.

### **Project Experience**

#### 2023 Console Assistant (Team Project)

Console bot with functions:

- Address Book add new contacts to the phonebook, together with birthday, email and address information. Additional features: edit and delete contacts, announce the next birthdays.
- Notebook add notes together with their title and tags. Additional features: add new tags, search by tags and key values, edit and delete notes.

Project link on Github, View Technologies: Python Core

#### 2023 **REAST API on FastAPI**

Implement a REST API to store and manage contacts using FastAPI and use SQLAlchemy to manage the database.

Project link on Github, View, Deploy

Technologies: FastAPI, SQLAlchemy, alembic, pytest, unittest, SQL database (elephant), redis, docker, deploy.

#### 2023 Site of Quotes on Django

Django implementation of the analog of the Quotes to Scrape website.

Project link on Github, View, Deploy

Technologies: Django, SQL database (render.com), redis, docker, deploy.

# **Working Experience**

# 2013 - currently

Company: Igor Sikorsky Kyiv Polytechnic Institute, Department of Applied Physics

Position: Associate Professor of Applied Physics

#### Responsibilities:

- Teaching: Developing and conducting lectures, seminars and practical classes in various courses of applied physics.
- Research activity: Conducting scientific research in the field of applied physics. Publication of research results in scientific journals. Participation in conferences and symposia.

2005 - 2013 Company: Kyiv National University of Construction and Architecture, Department of Physics

Position: Assistant/Associate Professor of Physics.

# Sergiy Ponomarenko

Python Developer

# Soft Skills —

- Punctuality
- Result orientation
- Attentive to details
- Stress Tollerance

### **Achivements**

July 2023	IT Tools for Teachers Certificate	Global Logic Education
2023	<b>Python: basics and applications</b> Certificate	Stepik
2022	Math and Python Workshop Certificate	Stepik
2021	Good, good Python Certificate	Stepik

# **Education**

#### Developer

2023	Python Developer	GoIT Global
	Graduated the Python Core and Python Web course.	

#### Physicist

2001 – 2005	PhD in Physicsof Polymers Defend PhD Thesis in Polymer Physisc.	IMS NAS of Ukraine
1995 – 2001	Masters Degree in Physics Graduated from uni and majored in physics.	Mykolaiv State Univercity